NAME PRAVEENKUMAR KONDAPARTHI **DESIGNATION** Technology Specialist

MOBILE#: +91 98484 .68149





Domain/Sub-Domain -

- Travel (Airline, Airport)
- Hospitality

Core Competency –

- Operational Excellence
- **Product Training**
- Organizational communication
- Team leadership

Education -

- Pursuing Full Stack Development from Scaler
- **Bachelors Of Arts** Gitam University - 2013

Profile Summary

Technical Specialist with 13+ years of overall and 8+ years of relevant experience in UI Development.

Proficient with Agile as well as water fall methodology, Making sure back logs are prioritized, estimated, requirements are clear, sprint planning and collaborative work space is available and track progress daily with help of standup meeting and burn down chart.

Technology Proficiency

Technology	ReactJs, JavaScript, jQuery, GraphQl, NextJS TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AntD and Material UI	
Tools	Visual Studio 2019,2022, VS code	
Operating Systems	Windows Servers, Windows XP, Windows 10 Pro	
Others	MS Office, VSS, CVS,	
Methodologies	Agile, Waterfall	

Professional Experience

Month- Year	Designation/ Role	Role Responsibilities
Mar -2022	Technology Specialist	Frontend Developer
June- 2013	Senior UI Engineer	Senior UI Engineer, worked on Agile based project development.
Oct 2009	Web Developer	Worked as Web developer, Designing the Web pages and implementation

Name of the Project: Betagro			
Duration	April 2023 – August 2023	Role	Sr. Software Engineer
Project Type	E-commerce Dashboard Development	Technology	ReactJs, Node.js, Material UI
My Responsibilities	 Working as individual contributor for Project Development. Working on frontend technology, ReactJs, Redux, Material UI Done PR Code review. Interact with Quality Assurance personnel during system testing phases of application development. 		

Name of the Project: HoneyComb Web			
Duration	Feb 2022 – April 2023	Role	Sr. Software Engineer
Project Type	Dashboard Web Application Development	Technology	ReactJs, NextJs, TypeScript, Graph
My Responsibilities	 Worked as individual contributor for development Project. Worked on storybook to build reusable components. Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use. Worked on frontend technology, ReactJs, NextJS, GraphQl, Typescript Worked closely with backend Developers. Involved in peer-to-peer code review sessions. Worked on PR code Review and updated the comments. Interact with Quality Assurance personnel during system testing phases of application development. 		

Name of the Project: Guest Services			
Duration	Oct 2019 – Nov 2021	Role	Sr. Software Engineer

Project Type	Application Development and Migration to React JS	Technology	React JS, REST WEB API, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
My Responsibilities	 Used JavaScript for Client Updated the Requirement Participated in designing a practices. Gathering requirements fr Developing new user-facin Building reusable compon Translating designs and w Optimizing components for devices and browsers. Involved in peer-to-peer of Built UI elements as per the Building front-end busines NodeJS developers to help Interact with Quality Assurdevelopment. Implementation of Busines 	-Side data binding, A and Design Docume and development of some business and defing features using Real ents and front-end lilly ireframes into high cor maximum performations application style gas applications while applications of the applications of t	software using agile development fining specifications for the system. act.js. braries for future use. quality code. ance across a vast array of web-capable quide to use across the board. working closely with .net and ents for backend development. ang system testing phases of application

Name of the Project: Reservation module			
Duration	Mar 2013 – Sep 2019	Role	UI Engineer
Project Type	Application Development	Technology	HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass, KnockoutJs, ReactJS
My Responsibilities	 Gathering requirements from business and defining specifications for the system. Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code. Built UI elements as per the application style guide to use across the board. Involved in peer-to-peer code review sessions. Creating Style Guide for the new enhancements. Developing new user-facing features using React.js. Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use. Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers. Building front-end business applications while working closely with .net and NodeJS developers to help generate requirements for backend development. Interact with Quality Assurance personnel during system testing phases of application development. 		

Strengths

- Good Communication skills and interpersonal relations
- Ability to coordinate a team and learn the new technologies with little effort.
- Able to use own initiative, out of Box thinking, Good problem-solving skills as part of team.
- Adapt to any environment according to the situation.

Personal Details

Name : Praveen Kumar Kondaparthi

Father Name : Bhoomaiah

Date Of Birth : 13th June, 1985

Address : Sri Varsha Residency, Flat No. 601, H.No. 87, 88, RamaRao Nagar,

Kukatpally Hyderabad – 500072

Nationality : Indian

Sex : Male

Marital Status : Married

Languages Known : English, Hindi and Telugu